《貓鼠遊戲》  前情提要
Previously on White Collar
我打開了彼得的保險櫃
I broke into Peter's safe.
清單就在我手裡
I had the list in my hand.
我本打算帶著寶藏遠走高飛
I was ready to take the treasure and go.
那為何又改變主意
Then why didn't you?
我在這裡有了新生活
I have a life here.
如果我走了
I run on this,
就只能在記憶中重訪紐約了
And New York is just a memory for me.
-他偷了一幅拉斐爾  -純屬猜測法官大人
- He stole a Raphael!  - Conjecture, your honor.
還有  我是"追查"你
And I pursued.
這幅拉斐爾我可沒忘
And I haven't forgotten about the Raphael.
尼爾的信件裡有密碼
Neal coded his letters.
我們破譯了
And we cracked it.
還不知道是什麼意思  不過會查到的
Don't know what they mean yet, but we will.
-我是...  -克雷默探員
- I'm --  - Agent Kramer.
華盛頓藝品犯罪科主管
Head of the bureau's D.C. Art Crimes Unit.
這麼說彼得的能耐都是跟您學的
So you're the one who taught Peter everything he knows.
你我相見是早晚的事  卡夫瑞先生
I'd say this moment was inevitable, Mr. Caffrey.
-尼爾是我的線人  -也是你的朋友
- Neal's my C.I.  - He's also a friend.
你覺得騙子永遠不會悔改
You think once a con, always a con?
我認為他們遭殃時你得保護自己
I think you have to protect yourself when they fall.
寶藏在你手裡
You have the treasure.
-我沒偷  -你個混蛋
- I didn't steal it.  - You son of a bitch!
我不管  反正在你手裡
I don't care. You have it.
東西在哪
Where is it?
本來就在這裡
It was here.
他把東西轉移了
He already moved it.
蚊子  當然是他
Mozzie? Of course it was Mozzie.
我沒想到他動作這麼快
I didn't think he'd move it this fast.
這是什麼
What is it?
這是封來自美國緩刑局的信
This is a letter from the U.S. Probation Office.
因為你的傑出貢獻
"Because of your outstanding service,
包括奪回寶藏
"Including recovering the treasure
抓捕凱勒歸案
"and catching Keller,
美國緩刑局將召開一次聽證會
"The U.S. Probation office is convening a hearing
討論對於你的減刑事宜
to discuss the commutation of your sentence."
這是什麼意思
What's that mean?
說明你不用戴腳環了
It means no anklet.
不再受監控
No nothing.
你就要自由了
You could be a free man.
請正式陳述你的姓名
State your name for the record, please.
尼爾·喬治·卡夫瑞
Neal George Caffrey.
卡夫瑞先生  你清楚今天為什麼請你來嗎
Mr. Caffrey, do you understand why you're sitting here today?
清楚
I do.
聯邦檢察署為我申請了第35條
The U.S. Attorney has petitioned a rule 35 motion
假釋動議  如果獲得批准
on my behalf, which, if granted,
將減免我的刑期  並具結釋放
would commute my sentence and set about my own recognizance.
簡言之  你們想知道我是否有資格獲得自由
In essence, you want to know if I've earned my freedom.
看來你已經研究過了
You've done your homework.
是的  長官
Yes, ma'am.
在四年刑期中你已經服刑兩年
You've already served two years of a four-year sentence
受到特別探員彼得·博爾克的監控
under the supervision of Special Agent Peter Burke.
是的  長官
Yes, ma'am.
戴著追蹤腳環
While confined to a tracking anklet,
你協助博爾克探員
you've helped Agent Burke clear
取得了94%定罪率的驚人成績
an impressive 94% conviction rate.
我們合作很棒
We work well together.
看起來是
It would seem so.
最近逮捕的馬修·凱勒
The recent arrest of Matthew Keller,
是聯調局十大通緝犯之一
one of the FBI's top 10 most wanted fugitives,
並追回了一批他偷竊的珍貴藏品
the recovery of a priceless collection of artwork he stole
你真是改過自新的典型
You are the poster boy for reform.
誰能想到呢
Who would have thought?
你作為罪犯加入了司法系統
You came into this legal system as a criminal.
聽證會成員要弄清的問題是  你是否已改過
The question before this board today is -- have you changed?
我相信我改過了
I believe I have.
在接下來兩天中
Over the next two days,
我們將訪談一些和你親近的熟人
we'll be interviewing some of your closest acquaintances
以及同事
and colleagues.
然後我們會讓你回來進行最後陳述
Then we'll have you back to make a final statement,
屆時博爾克探員
at which time Agent Burke
將給出總結性建議
will give his summary recommendation.
還有問題嗎
Any questions?
沒有了  長官
No, ma'am.
不過我想說過去兩年是我一生
But may I say that the last two years of my life
最棒的...
have been the best --
兩天會給你足夠的時間進行陳述
You'll have time for all that two days from now.
是的  長官
Yes, ma'am.
令人讚歎啊  卡夫瑞先生
This is impressive, Mr. Caffrey.
希望你本人和文件中所描述的相符合
I hope the real you lives up to who you are on paper.
希望不辜負您的期望
I hope to exceed your expectation.
你可以自由離開了
You're free to go.
自由離開
"Free to go."
真是個鼓舞人心的短語
Quite an inspiring turn of phrase.
不過"自由留下"對我來說更合適
Except "You're free to stay" might be more appropriate.
感覺如何
How's it looking?
都有可能
Flip a coin.
無論委員會如何判決
Regardless of what the committee decides,
這裡就是我家了
this is my home now.
而我會一直在你身邊
And I am right beside you.
在同樣的紐約開始嶄新的生活
Make a brand-new start of it in old New York.
當你重新開始時
Well, when you make that brand-new start,
我有驚喜給你
I've got a surprise.
-什麼驚喜  -大驚喜
- What kind of surprise?  - A huge one.
能讓大犬星座都黯然失色
Makes Canis Majoris look like a night light.
不過我不會再多說
But I will say no more.
我也不問了
I'll ask no more.
看起來你的證人列表裡
There seems to be someone missing
少了一個人
from your commutation witness list.
抱歉
Yeah, sorry about that,
不過讓一位著名罪犯為我說話
but having a known felon speak for me
並不能證明我的品格變好了
doesn't qualify as a good character reference.
我是罪犯  不過是非著名
I am a felon, but I'm not known --
至少在司法圈非著名
at least in bureaucratic circles.
我承認
I stand corrected.
而且已經有很多人來支持我了
But I've already got plenty of people on my side.
伊利莎白  瓊  還有莎拉
Elizabeth, June...Sara.
-真的  -對
- Really?  - Yeah.
很好  那兩個小探員呢
Good. What about the demi-suits?
瓊斯和戴安  萬能牌
Mm. Jones and Diana? Wild cards.
那探員叔本人呢
And the suit himself?
考慮到之前發生事情
Well, considering everything that's happened --
關於寶藏  關於凱勒
with the treasure, with Keller --
彼得怎麼選擇都有可能
Peter could go either way.
你認為他決定了嗎
Think he's decided?
我不知道
I don't know.
等等
Hold on.
克雷默探員  華盛頓藝品犯罪科的老爺爺
Agent Kramer, the D.C. Art Crimes grand-pere  --
他也是證人
He's speaking?
克雷默應該只代表局裡
Kramer was supposed to submit a written report
提交文本材料
on behalf of the bureau.
如果他親自作證  那絕不是只走程序
If he's speaking in person, that's more than a formality.
那對你會有什麼影響
Well, what does that do to your chances?
我覺得不會有正面作用
Well, I can't imagine it improves them.
反正最壞的情況是他不同意
You know what? Worst-case scenario, he says no,
我繼續戴著腳環  跟著彼得
and I stay on the anklet with Peter.
在每個最壞的情況之後
Well, behind every worst-case scenario,
通常都有更壞的情況
there's a worse worst-case scenario.
你是不是就非得
Isn't there a child
怎麼敗興怎麼說啊
whose balloon you need to pop somewhere?
沒錯  消極是我的習慣
Yeah. Negativity -- force of habit.
我想  肯定沒什麼問題
I'm...sure it doesn't mean anything.
對  沒事
Yeah. Nothing.
進來
Come on in.
屋裡真香
Smells good in here.
小伊在烘焙
Yeah. El's been baking.
恭喜減刑
減刑慶祝蛋糕
A commutation cake.
我告訴過她為時尚早
Yeah, I told her it was a little premature.
親愛的  我另一個蛋糕也好了
Hey, honey. I got that other cake.
給你看看
Wait till you see it.
別氣餒
"Hang in there."
帶著腳環的小貓
Little cat with an anklet.
失敗安慰蛋糕
Consolation cake.
-朗姆酒  -放了不少
- Rum?  - Lots of Rum.
-那最好  -對
- That'll be good.  - Yes.
不管怎樣
Well, for what it's worth,
我會選擇一號蛋糕
I'm actually voting for cake number one.
謝謝
I appreciate that.
你們聊
You guys talk.
你決定了嗎
So, have you decided?
我打算怎麼說嗎  說真的
What I'm gonna say? Honestly...
沒有  還沒決定
No. I haven't.
什麼事重要到不能打電話
So, what's so important you couldn't call?
為什麼克雷默會參加聽證會
Why is Kramer speaking at my hearing?
別為這個緊張
Don't let that put you on edge.
彼得  我面前擺著兩個蛋糕
Peter, I'm staring at two cakes here.
一個表示慶祝
One celebrates my fate,
另一個表示安慰  我當然緊張
The other seals it -- I am on edge.
為什麼他會發言
Why is he here?
我不知道  不管什麼原因
I don't know. For whatever reason,
克雷默不讓我介入其中
Kramer has decided to keep me out of the loop on this.
-他不讓你知道  -對
- He's keeping you out?  - Yeah.
不過我有內線
But I've got an inside man.
克雷默那邊怎麼樣
How'd it go with Kramer?
他讓我查文件到凌晨三點
He had me digging through files till 3:00 A.M.
他想證明什麼
What's he trying to prove?
不知道
I don't know.
說起卡夫瑞
When he talks about Caffrey,
他總是誇獎他的出色能力
he talks about him in glowing terms.
我注意到了
I noticed that.
他似乎很欣賞他
He seems to respect the hell out of him.
可他在查尼爾在監獄裡寄給凱特
But he's digging into the coded letters
那些密碼信件
Neal sent Kate from prison.
克雷默破譯了密碼
And now that Kramer's cracked the code,
他確信他會找出些什麼
he's convinced he'll find something.
是  不過是什麼呢
Yeah. But what?
彼得
Petey!
你好嗎
How are you?
我很好
I'm good.
在這裡辦公真有意思
It's an interesting place to set up shop.
你不覺得在辦公室裡更舒服嗎
You sure you wouldn't be more comfortable in an office?
我不想佔用其他人的房間
Well, I don't want to intrude on someone else's house.
在這裡我可以把東西都鋪開
And this lets me spread out.
這間房就是我們找出真相的地方
And this is the room where we find the truth.
應該會成功
That's how it's supposed to work.
我要伸伸腿
I need to stretch my legs.
跟我走走
Walk with me.
你有什麼想法
You've got something on your mind?
你還在查尼爾的卷宗
You're still pulling Neal's casework.
是不是有什麼事情該讓我知道
Is there something going on I should know about?
的確有  我很擔心你  彼得
Matter of fact, there is. I'm worried about you, Pete.
擔心
You're worried?
八音盒  加裡特·福勒  U型潛艇
Yeah. The music box, Garrett Fowler, e U-boat.
這些卷宗讀著像低俗小說
These 515s read more like pulp fiction
而不像案件總結
than case summaries.
你什麼意思
What are you saying?
你知道我什麼意思
Well, you know what I'm saying.
你在掩護他
You're covering for him.
不是嗎
Well, you're not?
事情很複雜
It's complicated.
我很能體會
If anyone gets it, I do.
他是你的朋友
He's your friend.
是的  菲利
He is, Phil.
我要保證他不會傷害你
And I want to make sure he's not gonna hurt you.
你希望他回到監獄
You want him back behind bars?
不是的  彼得
No, Pete.
他的價值不止於此
He's much too valuable for that.
什麼意思
Meaning?
我要尼爾為我工作  去華盛頓
I want Neal working for me. in D.C.
本字幕由 YYeTs · 人人影視 原創翻譯製作
「WEB&藍光版美劇專業戶」再加工製作
僅供學習 禁止用於任何商業盈利行為
如需其它劇集字幕  請登陸新浪微博（WEB藍光版美劇專業戶）
或發郵件：lj20090303@163.com
貓鼠遊戲 [妙警賊探]
第三季第16集（季終）
你第一次見到尼爾·卡夫瑞是什麼時候
When did you first meet Neal Caffrey?
他從監獄裡出來的那天
The day he was released from prison.
他們把他送到一個破敗不堪的小旅館裡
They had sent him to this horrible little fleabag motel.
你收留一個重罪犯  難道就不害怕嗎
And you had no qualms about taking in a convicted felon?
當然不會  尼爾沒問題
Absolutely not. Not Neal.
在我丈夫去世後
You see, after my husband passed,
我獨自一人住在空蕩蕩的大房子裡
I...I was living in this big, empty house.
尼爾改變了這一切
And...Neal changed all of that.
我覺得他是上天給我的恩賜
I think of him as a blessing.
拜倫和我一直想要個兒子
Byron and I always wanted a son.
我真希望他還活著
I wish he was still alive...
這樣他就能見到尼爾了
So that he could finally meet him.
艾靈頓太太  在你看來
Ms. Ellington, in your opinion,
應該給尼爾·卡夫瑞減刑嗎
does Neal Caffrey deserve for his sentence to be commuted?
當然
Of course.
應該的
Yes.
你們一定要讓他重獲自由
And you must let him go free.
情況如何
How'd it go?
姐搞定了
I nailed it.
很好
Nice.
你在想什麼呢
What are you thinking?
我在想我們需要第三個蛋糕了
I'm thinking we need a third cake.
上邊寫什麼
One with a file in it?
寫"一路順風"
One that says "Bon voyage."
克雷默不想放走尼爾
Kramer doesn't want to put Neal away.
他想讓尼爾去華盛頓為他工作
He wants to keep him for himself in D.C.
他想跟你搶尼爾
He'd take Neal away from you?
說是為我好  但這不是
For my own good, but that's not...
怎麼回事
What is it?
有天晚上  從日落到日昇
One night, from sunset to sunrise,
我給了尼爾完全豁免權
I gave Neal full immunity
要他對我坦白一切
to tell me everything he'd ever done.
他真坦白了
Wow. And he did?
沒錯  全坦白了
Boy, he did.
但他有完全豁免權
But he has full immunity.
那是我許他的  不是局里許的
It was my immunity, not the bureau's.
如果克雷默發現了這些事
If Kramer digs up these things
尼爾可能會量重刑
Neal could get the maximum.
別想華盛頓了  別想腳環了
Forget D.C. Forget the anklet.
他可能重回監獄
He could go back to prison.
把牢底坐穿
For a long, long time.
你告訴他了嗎
Have you told him?
-沒  -親愛的
- No. - Hon...
我不能
I can't.
如果尼爾感到威脅  他會惹更多的麻煩
When Neal's threatened, he gets in even more trouble.
和克雷默談談  他是你的朋友
Talk to Kramer. He's your friend.
他不瞭解自己正在打開的潘多拉魔盒
He doesn't know the Pandora's box he's opening.
我在看週一要處理的案件
I'm just skimming Monday's caseload,
想要預習一下
trying to get a head start.
這起嘉寶沃斯卡的保險詐騙案看起來很有意思
This Grabowska insurance fraud looks pretty promising.
我喜歡你積極的態度
I like that attitude.
我在想你什麼時候
I wondered how long it would be
才會回來見我
before you came back to see me.
菲利普  我們得談談
Philip. We need to talk.
我想也是
I suppose we do.
你發現了尼爾的什麼事
What do you have on Neal?
要談的不是這個
That's not what this is about.
尼爾需要被人管著
Neal needs boundaries.
我知道
I know that.
是嗎
You do?
我跟你說過我的線人  我的"尼爾"
I told you about my C.I. My "Neal."
是  你們很親密
Yeah. You were close.
比親密還親密  他就像我兒子一樣
We were more than close. He was like a son.
真是的  我還自以為可以讓他改邪歸正
Hell, I thought I'd brought him all the way around,
但他本性難改
but he couldn't change who he was.
就因為你給你的線人戴上了手銬
Well, you know, just because you slapped cuffs on your C.I.
並不意味著我和尼爾也會步後塵
Doesn't mean that I'll have to do the same to Neal.
你知道青蛙和蠍子的故事嗎
You know the story of the frog and the scorpion?
尼爾就是蠍子
Neal's the scorpion.
他本性愛蜇人  他會咬你
He can't help who he is. But he will sting you.
凱特·莫羅
郵政信箱  3279
紐約主街
你倆都會溺水
And you'll both drown.
在華盛頓  我可以盯住他
In D.C., I can keep an eye on him.
那過了兩年他重獲自由後呢
What happens in two years, when he's a free man?
誰說他會自由
Who's to say he will be?
這就是你的目的
That's what you're after.
你想用你掌握的全部線索
You want to use whatever you find
來無限延長他的刑期
to extend his sentence indefinitely.
這樣對大家都好
It's best for all concerned.
菲利
Phil --
他能施展自己的才華
He gets to do what he's so damn good at,
而不會淪落監獄  或者下場更慘
and he won't end up being locked away or worse.
我覺得他不該重獲自由
I don't think he should go free.
你說真的嗎
You mean that?
是的
I do.
紐約傳票
關於  尼爾·卡夫瑞
送交  斯博保險公司
我之前還沒有決定  但現在決定了
Until this moment, I didn't, but no.
莎拉
Sara.
尼爾不能重獲自由
Neal should not go free.
兩年後  他的刑期結束
In two years time, when his sentence is over,
他就有權決定自己的生活
He's earned that right to decide his own life.
彼得
Peter...
在那之前  尼爾在這裡  和我在一起
And until then, Neal's staying here, with me.
克雷默想要傳票我的文件嗎
Kramer is going to subpoena my files?
看來我曾非常接近拉斐爾的畫作
That means I was close to the Raphael.
是的
Yes.
我就知道  是你偷的
I knew it! You stole it!
被你發現了
You caught me.
尼爾
Neal!
這太棒了
This is so great!
我花了好多年時間找那幅畫
I've spent years looking for that painting.
我有多接近
How close was I?
克雷默破譯了一封我在監獄裡寫的加密信
Kramer cracked a coded letter that I wrote in prison
其中有藏匿地點的一部分
that includes a partial address of where I hid it.
你認為我有另外一部分嗎
So you think I have the other part?
我知道你有
I know you do.
天啊  我差點就查出來了
My God. I was so close.
沒錯  確實
Yes, you were.
我們多年前就賠了保險金
Well, we already paid out that claim years ago.
你欠斯博公司1千5百萬
You owe Sterling Bosch $15 million.
如果我不蹲監獄  我會想法子弄錢的
If I stay out of prison, I will work it off.
監獄寫信裡的加密地址
So, a coded address in a prison letter --
看起來很冒險啊
That seems kind of chancy.
我沒寫郵編
I left off the zip code.
那地方又是在主街上
And the address is on main street.
你知道美國有多少條主街嗎
You know how many main streets there are?
可能有上千條
Probably thousands.
那時有19364條
19,364 -- at the time.
那克雷默找到的地址毫無用處
So the address Kramer found means nothing.
除非他拿到有郵編的那片
Unless he gets his hands on that zip code.
你要找的是這個嗎
Is this what you're looking for?
沒錯  正是
Yes, it is.
羅斯福島
Roosevelt Island?
我是在酒鬼郵遞員的垃圾堆裡翻到的
I found this digging through a boozy courier's trash.
我就知道不該放棄這條線索
I knew I shouldn't have given up this lead.
這是唯一的一份嗎
Is this the only copy?
不是  服務器上的所有文件都有電子拷貝
No. We keep electronic copies of everything on the server.
所以我丟掉這份也是無濟於事
So I can't just throw this one away.
確實
No.
拉斐爾裝貨收據
拒絕訪問
我已經沒有權限了
And I've been locked out.
-打擾一下  -有什麼可以幫您  先生
- Excuse me. - Can I help you out, sir?
我們來送傳票的
We're here to serve a subpoena.
我們要全部有關
We need all the files related
拉斐爾《聖喬治亞和蛟龍》的資料
to Raphael's Saint George And The Dragon.
聯調局
FBI.
斯博公司
Sterling Bosch.
我是莎拉·埃利斯
This is Sara Ellis speaking.
-埃利斯女士  -我是聯調局探員克雷默
- Ms. Ellis. - Special agent Kramer, FBI.
克雷默探員  有什麼能為你效勞的先生
Agent kramer! What can I do to help you, sir?
我手下的探員給你辦公室送了張傳票索要
My agents are serving a subpoena at your office for all
一切有關拉斐爾《聖喬治亞和蛟龍》的資料
the files to related Raphael's Saint George And The Dragon.
我到底該怎麼辦
What the hell am I supposed to do?
爭取點時間
Just buy me some time.
先生  您肯定聽說了吧
Well, sir, you must have heard.
聽說了什麼
Heard what?
我們今早找回了那幅畫
We recovered the painting this morning.
你今早找回了拉斐爾的畫嗎
You recovered the Raphael this morning?
上頭要求我暫時保密
I was told to keep it under wraps
畢竟還有些細節要處理一下
as we're still working out the details.
那畫現在在哪裡
Well, where's the painting now?
-在鑒定師手上  -很好
- With our authenticator. - Good.
我會親自前往拿這幅畫
I'll be there myself to take possession of the painting
今天下班後就去
by end of business today.
希望你沒騙我
And I hope you're telling me the truth.
因為如果我六點鐘拿不到畫
Because if it's not there by 6:00,
就會以妨礙司法公正起訴你
I'll be charging you with obstruction of justice.
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
我為你爭取到了六個小時
I bought you six hours.
如果那幅畫到時候還沒交到我手上
If that painting isn't in my hands by the end of the day--
肯定會的
It will be.
你和卡夫瑞先生的私人關係
Has your personal relationship with Mr. Caffrey
會影響你今天的證詞嗎
influenced your testimony today?
是的  肯定有影響
Yes. Most definitely.
這不是你第一次
This isn't the first time
-為卡夫瑞先生的事作證了吧  -確實
- you've testified regarding Mr. Caffrey, is it? - No.
六年前  我曾指證他
Six years ago, I testified against him.
沒錯  在他被判偽造罪的審訊上
Yes. At the trail where he was convicted of forgery?
是的
Yes.
我竭盡全力地追查他
And I went after him with everything I had.
我罵他是騙子  小偷
I called him a liar and a thief
甚至是反社會分子  我可是真心的
and probably a sociopath, and I meant every word of it.
那什麼改變了
So, what changed?
尼爾改變了
Neal did.
尼爾  你在哪
Neal? Where are you?
你知道的
You know where I am.
你在羅斯福島纜車上
You're at the Roosevelt Island Tram.
你在可活動範圍的最邊緣
You're at the edge of your radius.
克雷默在查拉斐爾畫的事
Kramer is going after the Raphael.
你記得不久前的一個夜晚
You'll recall a night not long ago
你說我有豁免權嗎
when you said I had immunity?
我記得  尼爾
I remember, Neal.
你也該記得我說別做傻事
You'll recall that I said don't do anything stupid.
七年前  我做了一件傻事
Seven years ago, I did something stupid.
克雷默在追捕以前的尼爾·卡夫瑞
Kramer's going after the old Neal Caffrey.
我今天需要走出兩英里半徑區域
I need more than two miles today.
該死  尼爾  你這樣正中克雷默下懷
Damn it, Neal, you're playing right into Kramer's hands.
你要是被抓了
You get caught,
他就會抓到你持有贓物
he's got you on possession of stolen goods.
加上你的前科  會被判二十五年的
With your prior, that's 25 years.
我無法撤銷以前做過的事
I can't undo what's already been done.
但我可以歸回不屬於我的東西
But I can get back what's not mine.
我得走了
I got to go.
彼得  拜託  擴大我的活動範圍吧
Peter, please, extend my radius.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
去打開一扇我不想打開的門
To open a door I didn't want to have to open.
尼爾  尼爾
Neal? Neal!
拜託  彼得
Come on, Peter.
電子監控小組
Electronic monitoring compliance unit.
我是聯調局的博爾克
This is Burke, FBI.
拜託
Come on.
謝了  兄弟
Thank you, buddy.
這號碼挺陌生的
I don't recognize this number.
安靜聽著  蚊子  克雷默在調查拉斐爾畫作
Silent running, Moz. Kramer's after the Raphael.
尼爾  你在哪
Neal, where are you?
在去羅斯福島的纜車上
On a tram headed for Roosevelt Island.
真的嗎  羅斯福島  為什麼
Really? Roosevelt Island? Why?
晚些再解釋
I'll explain later.
現在我要你給我弄個交通工具
Right now I need you to find us transportation.
我可能需要你幫我返回
I may need your help getting back.
再見
Bye.
我是尼爾
It's Neal.
尼爾
Neal.
海倫
Helen.
好久沒見了  自從
I haven't seen you since --
自從我逃走那天起
Since the day I ran away.
真好
This is nice.
你還住在河畔
Still living by the river, I see.
這裡成了我家
It's become my home.
今年是冷春
It's been a cold spring,
但繡球花還是重新綻放了
but the hydrangea are coming back.
在這裡嗎
Is it here?
在
It is.
你能待多久
How much time do you have?
大概十分鐘
Maybe 10 minutes.
那我們就好好利用吧
Then let's make the most of it.
瓊斯  能精確定位卡夫瑞在島上的位置嗎
Jones, can you pinpoint where Caffrey is on Roosevelt Island
可以  他貌似在4221主街
Yeah. Looks like he's at 4221 main street.
我這就去
On my way.
你氣色不錯
You look good.
沒什麼變化
The same.
得了
Please.
都差不多十五年了
It's been nearly a decade and a half.
是啊  那是我十八歲的生日
Yeah, it was my 18th birthday.
對  我算是毀了你的生日
Yeah, I kind of ruined that one for you.
讓一個孩子聽到那種消息確實可怕
It was a hell of a thing for a kid to hear.
我為你保留的
I saved this for you.
-你和你父親  -天哪
- You and your father. - My God.
你的眼睛還是很像他
You still have his eyes.
說真的
Truth.
我告訴你自己做過的事之後  你恨我嗎
Do you hate me for telling you what I did?
不恨
No.
不  我媽說他死了
No, my mom told me he was dead.
說他是壯烈犧牲的  但你告訴了我真相
Said he died a hero, but you told me the truth.
他是個壞警察
He was a dirty cop...
而且他還沒死
And he's not dead.
你當時都準備投身警界了
You were gonna go and join the force.
我告訴你媽
I told your mother,
"只要他一進警校
"The moment he sets foot in the police academy,
肯定會聽到風言風語"
he's gonna get an earful."
說真的
Truth.
我爸一直都腐敗嗎
Was my father always corrupt?
我們剛做警探那年相遇並成為了搭檔
We met when we became partners as first-year detectives.
他當時  是最棒的
He was the best... then.
而邪惡轉瞬即至
the evil came after.
但你來不是為了這個吧
But that's not why you're here.
不是
No.
4221主街
4221 main street.
是棟高樓
It's a high-rise.
對  我排查了所有房客
Yeah, I ran all the tenants.
14-E的住戶已經被標上了
The person in 14-E's been flagged.
被誰標上了
Flagged by whom?
聯邦法警
The marshals.
E·帕克爾正在接受證人保護
E. Parker's in witness protection.
謝了  瓊斯
Thanks, Jones.
給你  保管得很好  沒打開過
Here it is. Kept it safe. Didn't open it.
郵戳就是你被捕的前一天
It's postmarked the day before you were arrested.
對
Yeah.
凱特從沒來拿過嗎
Kate never came to get it?
-那個黑髮的美女  -對
- The pretty girl with the dark hair. - Yeah.
她來過  大概五年前吧
She did. Almost five years ago now.
但她沒拿走
But she didn't take it?
她改變主意了
She changed her mind.
說想要你留著
Said she wanted you to have it.
我媽媽呢  你是否曾
What about my mom? Did you ever --
沒有
No.
沒她的消息  你爸的也沒有
I haven't seen or heard from her -- or your father --
好多年了
It's been years.
我得承認我很好奇
I have to admit I'm curious.
這裡面到底有什麼特殊的東西
What is in there that's so special?
我想用它來換回我曾經的日子
Something I took trying to get back a life I lost,
它卻一直在向我討債
and it's been chasing me ever since.
最好別讓它抓到你
Better not let it catch you.
我很抱歉來這兒
Listen -- coming here, I'm sorry.
聯調局也會來這  他們會盤查
The FBI is gonna show up. They'll ask questions.
反正這島對我來說也有點小
This island was getting a little small for me anyway.
你走吧
Now, go.
謝謝
Thank you.
為所有的一切
For everything.
我想知道裡面是什麼嗎
Do I want to know what's in there?
合理推諉
Plausible deniability.
走吧  我們去坐纜車
Come on, let's catch that tram.
我的車在對岸
My car's on the other side.
E·帕克爾是誰
Who is E. Parker?
我從沒告訴過任何人
I've never told anyone this --
蚊子都沒
not even Moz.
你要接電話嗎
You gonna get that?
彼得  我是戴安
Peter, it's Diana.
我和克雷默在一起
I'm with Kramer.
他知道卡夫瑞在羅斯福島
He knows Caffrey's on Roosevelt Island.
你在哪
Where are you?
我們在曼哈頓這邊的纜車出站口
We're at the tram terminal, Manhattan side.
該死
Damn it.
怎麼了
What's going on?
你和卡夫瑞在一起
You're with Caffrey.
對  我們正往你們那邊走
Yeah. And we're headed right to you.
首先說一下
Let me first say
博爾克探員和我結婚已有12年
that Agent Burke and I have been married for 12 years.
我們的關係基於尊重  欣賞和信任
It's a partnership that's built on respect, admiration, and trust.
這有什麼關聯性嗎
And how is this relevant?
彼得和尼爾的關係也是基於同樣的因素
Peter's relationship with Neal is based on the same elements
你丈夫信任尼爾
Your husband trusts Neal?
是的  關鍵時候
He does. When it counts.
關鍵時候
When it counts?
尼爾曾是騙子
Well, Neal was a con man.
我不知道你是否願意讓他和你妹妹約會
I don't know if you'd want him dating your sister.
我能收回那句話嗎
Can I take that back?
不能
No.
是這樣的  彼得和尼爾一起
Listen -- Peter and Neal together,
他們會吵架拌嘴
they argue and bicker.
但最終  關鍵時刻
But in the end -- when it counts --
彼得容忍尼爾  因為尼爾值得
Peter puts up with Neal because he's worth it.
卡夫瑞先生應該獲得減刑嗎
Should Mr. Caffrey's sentence be commuted?
是的
Yes.
這可不妙
This is not good.
不妙  我們一出去
No, we ride this out,
你又得再坐二十年牢
and you're put away for 20 years.
也許還有別的出路
Well, maybe there's another way.
什麼
What?
不行  想都別想
No. Forget that.
要是掉下去你就死定了
You'll never survive the fall.
我不會跳
I'm not gonna to jump.
那你準備怎麼做
Then what the hell are you planning?
幫忙我就告訴你
Help me out and I'll tell you.
不行  先告訴我  我再幫你
No, tell me, then I'll help you out.
你先幫
You first.
好吧
Fine.
謝謝
Thank you.
然後呢
And?
我要跳到另一輛纜車返回羅斯福島
And I'm doubling back toward Roosevelt Island.
祝我好運吧
Wish me luck.
什麼  不  尼爾  太瘋狂了
What? No. Neal, that's crazy.
該死  快給我回來
Damn it, get back in here!
尼爾
Neal!
你跳不過去的
You'll never make it!
尼爾
Neal!
什麼事  蚊子
What's up, Moz?
尼爾  你有空嗎
Neal, you got a second?
現在有
I do now.
你那兒聽著風挺大的
It sounds windy where you are.
確實  什麼事
Yeah. What is it?
莎拉和我有個計劃
Sara and I have a plan.
你還在羅斯福島嗎
Are you still on Roosevelt Island?
就快到了
I will be soon.
我已經設計好了一條逃跑路線
I've carved out an escape route.
在第五街和東街交匯處
Meet me at the traffic circle
交通轉盤那裡等我
where road 5 and east road connect.
馬上去
I'm on my way.
你能告訴我發生了什麼事嗎
You gonna tell me what happened up there?
我追蹤尼爾到了羅斯福島
I tracked Neal to the island.
我正要帶他回來
I was bringing him back --
-那他在哪  -他本該跟我在一起
- Then where is he?  - He'd be here with me now
偏偏你這邊一堆槍指著他
if you hadn't thrown a dozen guns at his face.
這還成我的錯了
This is my fault?
你逼得越緊  他就越會跑
You box him in, he's gonna run.
你根本駕馭不了他  只有我能
You have no idea how to handle him. I do.
顯然
Clearly.
告訴我  彼得
Tell me, Pete.
尼爾手上有畫嗎
Neal have the painting on him?
我沒看見
Not that I saw.
你是在駕馭他  還是在變成他
Are you handling him or becoming him?
長官  東行的纜車快到島上了
Sir. The eastbound tram is approaching the island.
繼續追捕卡夫瑞  我去市中心
Maintain pursuit on Caffrey. I'm heading downtown.
尼爾還有不到一小時時間去見莎拉·埃利斯
Neal's got under an hour to meet Sara Ellis.
如果他成功了  我會在那兒等他
If he makes it, I'll be waiting for him.
-快進去  -媽媽  你看
- Coming in now. - Mom, look at that.
尼爾
Neal?
蚊子  快開車
Moz, start the engine!
卡夫瑞善解人意
Caffery understands people.
你需要空間  他就一人待著
You need space, he keeps to himself.
你想要說話  他就靜靜聆聽
You need to talk, he listens.
你想喝啤酒  他就幫你倒
You need a beer, he'll pour.
但他會讓你感覺到他在屈尊紆貴
Although he'll let you know he's slumming it.
你支持他獲得減刑嗎
Do you support his commutation?
他工作非常出色
He's damn good at what he does,
我當他是我的朋友
and I consider him a friend.
但這不能改變
But that doesn't change the fact
他因偽造債券和越獄被定罪的事實
that he's a convicted bond forger and prison escapee.
我覺得他應該在局裡再干滿兩年
I think he should finish out his two years with the bureau
並心存感激
and be grateful...
因為這已經是我所見過的最好的交易了
that he's got the best damn deal I've ever seen.
好了  莎拉在斯博保險公司等你
Okay, Sara's waiting for you at Sterling Bosch.
如果你及時收工  你就圓滿了
If you can make the hand-off in time, you're golden.
"如果"
"If."
你成功的可能性有
Well, the odds of you making it are --
我知道  蚊子
I know, Moz.
但我別無選擇
But I don't have a choice.
不  你有
Yes. You do.
你把洛萊娜拿出來幹嘛
What's Lolana doing here?
在我們短暫的疏離時期
Well, during our brief alienation --
凱勒慘敗之前
before the whole Keller fiasco...
我把你應得的那份寶藏轉移出國了
I moved your portion of the treasure out of the country,
所以你不用想著索賠了
should you ever care to claim it.
你給我留了一半
You saved my half?
比一半稍微少點
Well, a little less than half.
我當時很生氣  有種告我去
I was angry -- sue me.
還是夠我們倆個
It's still worth more than either of us
一輩子花的
could ever spend in a lifetime.
我們可以跑  現在就跑
We could run. Right now.
永不回頭
Never look back.
我不想再逃了  蚊子
I don't want to run anymore, Moz.
所有分隊  請留意
All units, be on the lookout
一輛被偷的313號救護車
for stolen ambulance number 313.
那是我們  別說什麼不逃了
That's us. So much for not running.
我得做個了斷
I have to finish this.
我就知道你會這麼說
I somehow knew you were gonna say that.
但為了洛萊娜  我還是得試試
But for Lolana's sake, I had to give it a try.
走吧
Go.
我去引著聯邦政府的小嘍囉們
I'll lead the federal bloodhounds
游車河去
on a chase of the wild-goose variety.
謝了  蚊子
Thanks, Moz.
給
Here.
我是我沒成功  你和洛萊娜需要憑這個
If I don't make it, you and Lolana will need that
自己去買座島了
to get to the island without me.
你會成功的
You'll make it.
莎拉
hey, Sara.
你在哪兒
Where are you?
幾條街外
A few blocks away.
在大廳見我  很快了
Listen -- meet me in the lobby. It's gonna be close.
尼爾  我
Neal, I --
尼爾
Neal.
莎拉  有尼爾的消息嗎
Sara, have you heard from Neal?
他拿到畫了
He's got the painting,
但他沒擺脫掉克雷默
But he's not gonna get past Kramer.
可能他根本不需要
He may not have to.
五分鐘內安排一場跟你們老闆的會談
Get us a meeting with your boss in the next five minutes.
-我盡力  -不是盡力  是一定要
- I'll try. - Don't try. Do it.
我看到卡夫瑞了
I have eyes on Caffrey.
不妙
Not good.
珍珠酒店往東
Heading east on Pearl.
我肯定會反悔的
I'm gonna regret this.
什麼  給我把這東西挪開
What?! Hey! Hey! You got to move that thing!
做不到的  女士
No can do, ma'am.
你在幹什麼
What are you doing?!
尼爾
Neal!
上車
Get in!
克雷默探員  卡夫瑞跟丟了
Agent Kramer, we lost Caffrey.
所有人去斯博公司
All units fall back to Sterling Bosch.
包圍整棟建築
Form a perimeter around the building.
-謝了  -祝你好運  卡夫瑞
- Thank you. - Good luck, Caffrey.
你們的提議
Your proposal...
似乎極其反常
It all seems highly irregular.
是的  博世先生
Yes, Mr. Bosch,
但您得承認  這種反常
But you can admit that irregularity
我過去可是屢試不爽
has worked very well for me in the past.
我是給您提供了一個
And I'm offering you an opportunity
五分鐘內賺到1千5百萬的機會
to make $15 million in five minutes.
博爾克探員  你能向我保證這是合法的嗎
Agent Burke, you can assure me this is all legal?
不合法的話  我根本不會在此
I wouldn't be here if it weren't.
我要做什麼
What do I have to do?
只需要簽幾項啟動文件  先生
Just sign some start paperwork, sir.
應該說這一刻是注定的
I'd say this moment was inevitable,
不是嗎  尼爾
wouldn't you, Neal?
我就知道你很適合
I knew you could be reasonable.
你肯定會在華盛頓大放異彩的
I think you might take a real shine to D.C. after all.
別指望了
Don't count on it.
你來盡主人之誼吧  彼得
You do the honors, Pete.
我真該聽你的話  現在落他手裡了
I should have listened to you. I played right into his hands
還沒結束呢
It's not over yet.
拉斐爾的《聖喬治亞和蛟龍》
Raphael's Saint George And The Dragon.
開創性傑作
A seminal work.
勞駕
Excuse me.
這幅畫是斯博保險的財產
That painting is property of Sterling Bosch Insurance.
勇氣可嘉  埃利斯女士
Valiant Effort, Ms. Ellis.
這是刑事犯罪的證據
This is evidence in a criminal investigation.
什麼刑事犯罪
Investigation into what?
B類贓物持有罪
Class "B" possession of stolen property.
閣下哪位
And you are?
溫斯頓·博世  這位年輕女士的老闆
Winston Bosch. This young lady works for me.
我沒看到有什麼人持有贓物
I don't see anyone here with stolen property.
這幅畫
This painting --
屬於斯博公司
Belongs to Sterling Bosch.
我們雇了卡夫瑞先生幫我們鑒定一下
We hired Mr. Caffrey to authenticate it for us.
這是扯什麼蛋
The hell you did.
是我請的  給
Yes. I did. Here.
卡夫瑞先生是傑出的藝術品專家
Mr. Caffrey is quite the art expert.
甚至聯調局都請他當鑒定師
He's even worked for the FBI as an authenticator.
我點我可以作證
I can attest to that.
如果他足以勝任你們的要求
And if he's good enough for you,
當然也可以勝任我們的要求
He's good enough for me.
你也參與其中了
You're part of this?
卡夫瑞先生
Well, Mr. Caffrey,
你對本幅作品的專業評估如何
what's your professional assessment of this piece?
絕對是拉斐爾真跡
That is definitely the real Raphael.
我可以名譽保證
I'd stake my reputation on it.
太好了
Excellent.
你的酬勞  1200元
And for your services -- $1,200.
抱歉了  尼爾在為我們工作期間不能
Sorry. Neal's not allowed to accept payment
接受報酬
while he works for us.
那更好了
Even better.
-回見  卡夫瑞  -回見
- See you around, Caffrey. - See you around.
你何不趕快回家
Why don't you head home?
好好休息一下  明天是個關鍵的日子
Get some rest. Got a big day tomorrow.
你這邊沒事兒吧
You gonna be okay?
我沒事的  走吧
I'll be fine. Go.
你背著我搞鬼
You went behind my back,
密謀妨礙司法公正
conspired to obstruct justice.
我可以說  你也一樣
I could say you did the same.
醒醒吧  彼得  睜開眼看看吧
Wake up, Petey! Open your eyes!
你不是他的拍檔  你是他的目標
You're not his partner. You're his mark!
他最擅長騙取別人的信任
This boy's run such a good confidence game,
他讓你以為
He's got you thinking
這些是你想要的
that you've come out ahead in all this.
你從什麼時候開始喪失對人性的信心了
When did you stop putting faith in people?
從他們不配讓我相信時開始
When they stopped deserving it.
這事兒沒完  彼得
This isn't over yet, Pete.
絕對沒完
Not by a long shot.
卡夫瑞先生  你應該獲得自由嗎
Mr. Caffrey, do you deserve to be free?
這不是由我來決定的
That's not for me to decide.
我不會坐在這裡給你演一出我已是
I won't sit here and give you some monologue
如何改過自新的獨角戲
about how reformed I am.
事實勝於雄辯
Actions speak louder than words,
希望我在聯調局服務期間的事實
And, hopefully, my actions while in service to the FBI
能勝於我的雄辯
say more than I can.
那你會如何利用你的自由呢
And what would you do with your freedom?
有一件事我可以確定
I can tell you one thing.
短時間內我哪裡都不會去
I won't be going anywhere anytime soon.
-哪兒都不去  -沒錯
-You won't? -No.
我在這裡很開心
I'm happy here.
有人曾對我說過
You know, someone once told me
我就像生活在美夢中  只是帶了腳環
my life is a dream with an anklet attached.
如果我明天一覺醒來而腳環還在
If I wake up tomorrow and that anklet is still on --
我有一份好工作  一間好住宅
I have a good job, a wonderful home...
一名拍檔  一名知己
a partner and a best friend.
一個家
A family.
但是醒來後  給自己的答案
But to wake up and answer only to myself...
對我來說意味著一切
That would mean everything.
我們要與另一位面談一下
We have one more interview to conduct
然後再做出決定
before we make our decision.
今天下午五點前通知你答案
You'll have an answer here today by 5:00 p.m.
謝謝
Thank you.
情況怎麼樣
How'd it go?
我感覺就那樣吧
As well as it could go, I think.
你知道最棒的是什麼嗎
You know what the nice thing is?
已經不重要了
It doesn't matter.
什麼意思
What do you mean?
你會走進去作證
You're gonna go in there and say your piece,
委員會會作出決定
and the board's gonna make their decision.
但不管有沒有腳環
But with or without my anklet,
到了週一早上  我會走出電梯
come Monday morning, I'm gonna step off that elevator
踏入21層的辦公室  開始工作
on the 21st floor and go to work.
你曾對說我  你從未騙過我
You once told me you never lied to me
也永遠不會騙我
and you never will.
現在我想知道一件事
So I need to know something.
克雷默和我第一次為德加畫作查你的時候
The first time Kramer and I went after you for the Degas,
你是怎麼換掉畫作的
How'd you switch the paintings?
我偷溜進頂層  偷梁換柱
I snuck up to the penthouse, pulled the swap,
從樓頂跳傘  在華爾街著陸
then base-jumped off the building and landed on Wall Street.
好吧  你沒說過
Fine. Don't tell me.
我得走了
I got to go in.
你在羅斯福島見的那個人
That person you saw on Roosevelt Island --
是誰
Who was it?
這事結束後
When this is over...
我會全告訴我
I'll tell you everything.
回見
See you soon.
他們已經在等你了  博爾克探員
They're ready for you now, Agent Burke.
謝了  亨利
Thanks, henry.
這是幹什麼
What is this?
這幾位執法官在等著尼爾·卡夫瑞一回來
These marshals are here to take Neal Caffrey
就把他送進監獄
into custody when he returns.
為了什麼
For what?
你要是聽進去我的話就知道了
If you had only listened to me.
-為了什麼  -危害公眾利益
- For what? - Public endangerment.
我們有一堆證人能證明
I've got a dozen eyewitnesses
他從纜車上跳了下來
who saw Caffrey hop that tram.
再加上躲避逮捕  妨礙司法公正
Combine that with evading arrest, obstruction of justice.
管他呢  也許再加條"亂穿馬路罪"來湊數
Hell, I may even throw in a jaywalking charge for good measure
我們的工作可不是復仇
We're not in the revenge business.
尼爾惹到你了  你就想傷害他
Neal pissed you off, and now you want to hurt him.
只是要控制他
Just control him.
尼爾有一堆的把柄
Neal's got a lot of skeletons.
我抓住一塊  讓他套上腳環
I'll pick one, slap that anklet on him,
就能讓他永遠留在華盛頓為我工作了
And he'll work for me in D.C. permanently.
你明白這其實對大家都好  明白嗎
You understand this is best for everyone, don't you?
明白嗎
Don't you?
我要去作陳述了
I have a statement to make.
請正式陳述你的姓名和
State your name and relationship to Neal Caffrey
與尼爾·卡夫瑞的關係
for the record, please.
特別探員彼得·博爾克
Special Agent Peter Burke.
自從尼爾·卡夫瑞的監管權轉移過來後
I've been Neal Caffrey's handler at the Federal
我一直是他在聯邦調查局的管理人
Bureau of Investigation since his release into our custody
你抓到的他嗎
You caught him?
抓了兩次
Twice.
你們應該瞭解  上次我抓到他時
And you should know, the last time I caught him,
他孤零零地坐在空蕩蕩的公寓裡
he was sitting alone in an empty apartment.
一無所有  無親無故
He had nothing. No one.
現在呢
And now?
他擁有了人生  在這裡有了真正的生活
He has a life. A real life here.
可以讓他腳踏實地  過體面的生活
One that keeps him grounded and decent.
正如你們所聽到的
As you've heard,
有很多人關心尼爾
there are many people who care about Neal,
而不只是把他視為一名罪犯
people who see him as more than just a criminal.
我承認他會令我沮喪
He's frustrating, I'll admit.
有時候會氣得我發瘋
He drives me crazy on his best days.
我並不能永遠知道尼爾在哪裡
I don't always have to know where Neal is
他想做什麼
or what he's up to.
但我知道  他有一顆善良的心
But I do know that he has a good heart
有原則
and a set of principles...
而六年前  當他只是扔到我桌子上
That weren't there six years ago when
某案卷的嫌犯時  他並沒有這個
he was just another case file that got dropped on my desk.
你以為卡夫瑞先生已經改過自新了嗎
Do you think Mr. Caffrey is reformed?
只要他還帶著腳環  我們永遠無從得知
As long as he's on that anklet, we'll never know.
我們可以在這裡坐到天荒地老
We can sit here until kingdom come
辯論尼爾·卡夫瑞到底何許人也
and debate over who is Neal Caffrey.
但只要我們還在栓著他
But as long as we keep him tethered,
只要我們還視他為罪犯
as long as we treat him like a criminal,
他就會永遠以為他真的是
He'll always think that he is one.
無論尼爾是公民  是線人  還是竊賊
Whether Neal is a citizen, a C.I., or a thief
這個決定必須要他自己來下
is a decision that needs to be put in his hands.
博爾克探員
Agent Burke...
-你好  -尼爾·卡夫瑞應該得到減刑嗎
- Hello?  - Should Neal Caffrey's sentence be commuted?
是的
Yes.
我認為尼爾應該得到自由
I'm saying Neal should be free.
抱歉  事態緊急
I'm sorry -- this couldn't wait.
彼得  卡夫瑞剪掉了腳環
Peter Caffrey's cut his anklet.
尼爾走了
Neal's gone.